Cultures collide. Hope survives.
American Factory is a documentary film directed by Steven Bognar.
In post-industrial Ohio, a Chinese billionaire opens a new factory in the husk of an
abandoned General Motors plant, hiring two thousand blue-collar Americans.
Early days of hope and optimism give way to setbacks as
high-tech China clashes with working-class America.
Self - Vice President, Fuyao, played by Junming 'Jimmy' Wang.
Self - U.S. Senator, Ohio, played by Sherrod Brown.
Self - Vice President, Fuyao Glass America, played by Dave Burrows.
Self - President, Fuyao Glass America, played by John Gauthier.
Self - Furnace Supervisor, played by Rob Haerr.
Self - Lamination Specialist, played by Cynthia Harper.
American Factory (Chinese: 美国工厂) is a 2019 American documentary film directed by Steven Bognar and Julia Reichert, about Chinese company
Fuyao's factory in Moraine, a city near Dayton, Ohio, that occupies Moraine Assembly, a shuttered General Motors plant.
The film had its festival premiere at the 2019 Sundance Film Festival.
It is distributed by Netflix, and is the first film acquired by Barack and
Michelle Obama's production company, Higher Ground Productions.
At the 92nd Academy Awards, American Factory won the
award for Best Documentary Feature.
The film explores themes of factory worker,
culture clash, ohio, chinese, american.